<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<refentry>
  <refmeta>
    <refentrytitle>wdcompile</refentrytitle>

    <manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
  </refmeta>

  <refnamediv>
    <refname><command>wdcompile</command></refname>

    <refpurpose>parse and compile WebDyne pages</refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>

  <refsynopsisdiv>
    <cmdsynopsis>
      <command>wdcompile [OPTIONS] FILE</command>
    </cmdsynopsis>
  </refsynopsisdiv>

  <refsection>
    <title>Options</title>

    <para><variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>-h, --help</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Show brief help message.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>-0</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Stop and display internal data structure after parsing
            with<classname> HTML::TreeBuilder</classname>. This stage shows
            the HTML syntax tree generated from the source file.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>-1</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Stop and display internal data structure after first stage
            of optimisation. In this stage any parts of the HTML tree that do
            not contain child tags that generate dynamic output are
            pre-rendered back into HTML</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>-2</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Stop and display internal data structure after second stage
            of optimisation. In this stage blocks that do generate dynamic
            code are analysed for child tags that can be pre-rendered back
            into HTML without affecting the dymamic components of the
            tree.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>-m, --meta</term>

          <listitem>
            <para>Show any WebDyne meta data found in the source file. WebDyne
            meta data are hints or instructions contained in the
            <markup>&lt;meta&gt;</markup> sections with the name "WebDyne". If
            found such meta data is removed from the resulting HTML parse tree
            and stored in a separate data structure. This option will show
            that data structire if it exists.</para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist></para>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>Description</title>

    <para>The <command>wdcompile</command> command displays the internal data
    structure used by WebDyne when compiling psp pages.</para>

    <para>WebDyne uses the same parsing and compilation routines as
    <command>wdcompile</command>. After compilation WebDyne optionally stores
    the resulting data structure to a cache directory using the Perl
    <classname>Storable</classname> module to speed up subsequent rendering
    operations.</para>

    <para>If the tree structure does not appear correct when debugging with
    <command>wdcompile</command> then it will probably not display as expected
    when rendered with WebDyne. Missing end quotes, closing tags and general
    HTML syntax problems can all make the parse tree misplace (or omit
    completely) blocks of HTML/WebDyne code.</para>

    <para>By default <command>wdcompile</command> will show the data structure
    after all parsing and optimisation stages have been completed. You can
    display various intermediate stages using the options below.</para>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>Notes</title>

    <para>The wdcompile will not run any code in the <code>__PERL__</code>
    section of a psp file. It will also not execute any WebDyne filters that
    may be called by the source file.</para>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>Examples</title>

    <para><command>wdcompile widget.psp</command></para>

    <para>Compile and display the completed internal WebDyne data structure of
    the file called widget.psp. The resulting output shows the data structure
    after the file is parsed, the rebuilt around any dynamic WebDyne
    tags.</para>

    <para><command>wdcompile -0 widget.psp</command></para>

    <para>Parse and display the very data structure of the widget.psp file at
    the lowest level - as interpreted by the HTML::Treebuilder module, with no
    optimisation at all.</para>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>Author</title>

    <para>Written by Andrew Speer, <email>andrew@webdyne.org</email></para>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>Copying</title>

    <para>Copyright © 2008-2010 Andrew Speer. Free use of this software is
    granted under the terms of the GNU General Public License (GPL)</para>
  </refsection>
</refentry>
